In 2015, Deep Mind made a breakthrough by
在 2015 年 DeepMind 取得了突破性的成果
designing an agent that learned to play video games better than humans.
他们设计了一个可以学会玩视频游戏的智能体 并且比人类玩家的能力更强
Yes, it's probably easy to write a program that plays pong
如果你知道电子游戏 “Pong” 的底层游戏状态
perfectly if you have access to the underlying game state,
或许可以轻松地编写一个玩这个游戏的程序
position of the ball, paddles, et cetera.
例如球的位置 挡板等
But this agent was only given raw pixel data,
但是这个智能体只能获得原始的像素数据
what a human player would see on screen.
即人类玩家在屏幕上看到的结果
And it learned to play a bunch of different Atari games, all from scratch.
它学会了从头开始玩各种不同的 Atari 游戏
They call this agent a Deep Q Network,
他们将这个智能体称之为深度 Q 网络
let's take a close look at how it works.
我们深入了解下它的工作原理
True to its name, at the heart of the agent is
正如它的名字所表示的含义 该智能体的核心是
a deep neural network that acts as a function approximator.
一个充当函数逼近器的深度神经网络
You pass in images from your favorite video game one screen at a time,
你一次传入一个你喜欢的视频游戏屏幕的图片
and it produces a vector of action values,
它会生成一个动作值向量
with the max value indicating the action to take.
最大值表示采取的动作
As a reinforcement signal,
根据强化信号
it is fed back the change in game score at each time step.
它会在每个时间步将游戏得分的变化往回馈送
In the beginning when the neural network is initialized with random values,
一开始 当神经网络初始化为随机的值时
the actions taken are all over the place.
采取的动作很混乱
It's really bad as you would expect,
正如你所预期的 效果很差
but overtime it begins to associate situations and sequences in
但是随着时间的推移 它开始将游戏中的情景和顺序
the game with appropriate actions and learns to actually play the game well.
与相应的动作关联起来 并且学会很好地玩游戏
Consider how complex the input space is.
输入空间非常复杂
Atari games are displayed at a resolution of 210 by 160 pixels,
Atari 游戏的分辨率为 210 x 160 像素
with 128 possible colors for each pixel.
每个像素有 128 种可能的颜色
This is still technically a discrete state space but very large to process as is.
这依然是一个离散状态空间 但是处理起来非常庞大
To reduce this complexity,
为了降低复杂性
the Deep Mind team decided to perform some minimal processing,
DeepMind 团队决定稍加处理
convert the frames to gray scale,
将帧转换为灰阶
and scale them down to a square 84 by 84 pixel block.
并缩小为 84 x 84 像素的正方形
Square images allowed them to use more optimized neural network operations on GPUs.
正方形图片使他们能够在 GPU 上使用更加优化的神经网络运算
In order to give the agent access to a sequence of frames,
为了使智能体能够访问一系列的帧
they stacked four such frames together resulting in
他们将四个此类帧堆叠起来
a final state space size of 84 by 84 by 4.
形成 84 x 84 x 4 的最终状态空间
There might be other approaches to dealing with
也许还有其他处理序列数据的方法
sequential data but this was a simple approach that seemed to work pretty well.
但是这个似乎是一个效果很好的简单方法
On the output side,
在输出端
unlike a traditional reinforcement learning setup
与传统强化学习设置
where only one Q value is produced at a time,
（一次仅生成一个 Q 值）不同
the Deep Q network is designed to produce
深度 Q 网络会为一个前向传递中的
a Q value for every possible action in a single forward pass.
所有可能的动作生成一个 Q 值
Without this, you would have to run the network individually for every action.
不这么处理的话 你需要单独为每个动作运行该网络
Instead, you can now simply use this vector to take an action,
现在 你可以直接根据该向量采取动作
either stochastically, or by choosing the one with the maximum value. Neat, isn't it?
要么是随机形式 要么选择值最大的动作 很简单 对吧
These innovative input and output transformations support
这些创新型输入和输出转换
a powerful yet simple neural network architecture under the hood.
支持在后台使用强大却简单的神经网络结构
The screen images are first processed by convolutional layers.
屏幕图片首先用卷积层处理
This allows the system to exploit spatial relationships,
使系统能够发现空间关系
and can sploit spatial rule space.
并探索空间规则空间
Also, since four frames are stacked and provided as input,
此外 因为将四个帧堆叠起来作为输入
these convolutional layers also extract some temporal properties across those frames.
这些卷积层还将从这些帧中提取时间属性
The original DQN agent used
原始 DQN 智能体
three such convolutional layers with RLU activation, regularized linear units.
使用了三个此类卷积层 并采用 ReLU 激活函数 即正则化线性单元
They were followed by one fully-connected hidden layer with RLU activation,
然后是一层采用 ReLU 激活函数的完全连接隐藏层
and one fully-connected linear output layer that produced the vector of action values.
以及一层完全连接的线性输出层 用于生成动作值向量
This same architecture was used for all the Atari games they tested on,
他们在所有接受测试的 Atari 游戏上应用了同一架构
but each game was learned from scratch with a freshly initialized network.
但是每个游戏都从头开始学习并使用重新初始化的网络
Training such a network requires a lot of data,
训练此类网络需要大量数据
but even then, it is not guaranteed to converge on the optimal value function.
但即使这样 也不能保证会收敛于最优值函数
In fact, there are situations where the network weights can oscillate or diverge,
实际上 在某些情况下 网络权重会因为动作和状态
due to the high correlation between actions and states.
之间的关系非常紧密而振荡或发散
This can result in a very unstable and ineffective policy.
这样会导致非常不稳定并且效率很低的策略
In order to overcome these challenges,
为了克服这些挑战
the researchers came up with several techniques that
研究人员想出了多个技巧
slightly modified the base Q learning algorithm.
稍微修改了基础 Q 学习算法
We'll take a look at two of these techniques that I
我们将了解其中的两个技巧
feel are the most important contributions of their work;
我认为这两个技巧是他们的成果中最重要的贡献
experience replay, and fixed Q targets.
即经验回放和固定 Q 目标